Chris Wallace award-winning product design executive

TWITTER

EMAIL

WEBSITE

PHONE

@chriswallace

chriswallace7@protonmail.com

chriswallace.net

972-837-7267

Professional Summary

Emmy-nominated founder and design leader with 16+ years of leadership in product and web design. Established record of pioneering innovative digital experiences for high-profile tech and media organizations including Google, Microsoft, Facebook, ESPN, The Boston Globe, and AMC Networks. Former agency executive at 10up, Lift UX (acquired).

Work Experience

Chief Experience Officer

UltraDAO Studios // 2021 - Present // Remote

Founded a bootstrapped decentralized web3 creative studio developing entertainment media IP, digital products and blockchain-based collectibles. Built and managed a team of artists, engineers, and creative production specialists. Achieved multi-million dollar revenue within its first six months. Raised \$250,000 for Trees for the Future to plant one million trees in sub-Saharan Africa, won "Best Environmental Initiative" at NFT NYC 2022. Executive Director for Woodies: Origin, official selection of the Aesthetica Short Film Festival 2023.

Vice President, Experience Design

10up (acquired) // 2017 - 2021 // Remote

Steered the design discipline at a global agency of 250+ staff spread across three continents and 16 countries. Fostered a culture of collaboration and co-design, which was instrumental in growing the design team from 5 to 20 professionals across 12 time zones. This initiative contributed to nearly doubling the agency's revenue (~95%) within four years. Spearheaded inclusive hiring practices diversifying team composition, and broadened design services to encompass content design, illustration, and more.

Principal Creative, Founder

Lift UX (acquired) // 2009 - 2017 // Remote

Led a boutique team of designers and engineers, crafting apps and websites for a varied clientele like AMC Networks, Frito-Lay, and GoDaddy. Launched interactive second-screen apps for acclaimed TV series, earning two Emmy nominations in the process. Managed a compact yet effective team of full-time and contract designers, elevating website traffic for the product division to two million monthly visitors. The successful journey culminated in an acquisition by 10up in 2017.

Front-end Developer

Enterprise Rent-A-Car // 2007 - 2009 // Clayton, MO

Engaged in developing front-end interfaces for B2B applications and B2C websites, working closely with UX designers and back-end Java engineers to roll out new applications. Handled weekly deployments for enterprise.com and other customer-centric platforms, while providing QA support for monthly release cycles.

Senior E-Commerce Web Designer

Network Solutions // 2006 - 2007 // Belleville, IL

Designed and developed front-end code for e-commerce storefronts for small businesses, maintaining stringent project timelines and adhering to client specifications.

Webmaster

Saint Louis Christian College // 2005 - 2006 // Florissant, MO

Primary web content owner, designed, developed, and maintained the college's online presence. During my tenure, the college experienced 60% growth, reaching full campus capacity the following year.

Skills

- * Design Management
- * Strategic Planning
- * Hiring & Personnel Management
- * Creative Direction
- * Design Systems
- * WordPress Design & Development
- * Resource Management
- * Professional Development Planning
- * Design Operations

- * Product Design
- * Visual & Brand Identity
- **★** Web3 (Blockchain & NFTs)
- * AI + Design Tooling
- * Information Architecture
- * Visual Design & Prototyping
- * Front-End Engineering
- * E-commerce Design
- * IP Development

Education

Missouri State University

Graphic Design // 2004 // Springfield, MO

Attended Missouri State University (formerly Southwest Missouri State) for Graphic Design.

Saint Louis Christian College

Religious Studies // 2002 - 2004 // Florissant, MO

Attended Saint Louis Christian College with a focus on Religious Studies.